My name is Anthony Maddaloni, I am a professional photographer from Austin, Texas.
I am going to talk about tripods.
This is my tripod.
I've had it for many many years.
It is a very sturdy, trusty tripod.
One thing I like about it, it is heavy and it is very very sturdy.
And pretty easy to bring around with me.
The first thing you can see, when it's collapsed, it's about two and a half feet in length.
It's not really long and it's easy to carry.
That's one thing that I do like about it.
It's got three legs and folds down.
Here it extends and locks.
I like tripods like this because they don't have the locks on them.
I found that some tripods I have that have the locks, they strip.
This just screws in and locks.
But that's me, it's what I prefer.
Other people like the other kind.
This is the head of the tripod.
It tilts like this and like this.
This is a very basic tripod.
A lot of tripods, the more professional kinds have levels on them.
So you would actually have a spirit level built into the tripod to make sure that you're level when you're focusing.
This is a pretty important factor.
I tend to use a level on my cameras.
I have a small level that I put on.
It's just easier for me to work that way.
There's no better or worse.
I do have tripods that have levels in them and they are, when I'm photographing architecture, extremely necessary for me to have.
Right here is where your camera will screw into.
And again you just want to place it.
You don't want to put your camera into a tripod too tight.
I have seen people put them on so tight that it's really hard to get them off.
So don't go crazy, you just want to screw that in.
Some tripods also have what's called a speed mount, meaning that you can put it on your tripod and take it off very quickly.
This one doesn't, but again I like it because it's just so simple and so easy for me to use.
And this is a tripod.